# Lilliana Smith | Software Engineer

Portfolio.com | 781-960-4112 | lillianarsmith97@gmail.com | lin/lily-smith | github.com/LSmith97

#### **SUMMARY**

I am a creatively driven, solutions-minded full-stack software engineer with a passion for intuitive design and function. My previous military experience informs everything that I do: from my ability to adapt and adjust plans quickly to finding efficient, concise solutions for challenging problems.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages - JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Python, SQL, Mongo, JSON, Typescript, EJS, DTL | Database - PostgreSQL, MongoDB Libraries and Frameworks - React (class based and hooks), Express.js, Django, Jquery, Bootstrap

Other - RESTful Routing, JSON api, MVC architecture

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **Network Administrator**

**United States Marine Corps** 

2015-2019

- Installed, operated, and maintained LAN and WAN enabling command and control.
- Daily tasks such as routing/switching configuration, premise wiring, installation of network components.
- Establishing technical control sites, conducting fault analysis, circuit testing and end to end troubleshooting.
- Maintaining records on activation/deactivation of communication links and maintenance action performed.

### **Grocery Associate**

Wegmans Food Markets

2021-2022

- Proactively offered customer assistance or services
- Ensured a fresh and appealing display by keeping cases and shelves clean and well stocked by front-facing, checking codes, and rotating.
- Ensured compliance with all applicable health and sanitation procedures and adhered to safe work practices.

# **PROJECTS**

Pixel Quest | JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Front-End Web Developer | 1 Week | Live | Github

- Built Responsive Front-End using HTML and JavaScript to create a responsive website for mobile and desktop
- Developed front-end styling using CSS to render a responsive, appealing, and accessible user experience
- Used JavaScript to Create Game Logic and Handle User Interaction to scale code for future development

**Mingo** | <Team Project> | Express, MongoDB, Node.js, EJS, Javascript, HTML, CSS Backend Lead | 1 week | <u>Live</u> | <u>Github</u>

- Used Express and Mongoose to handle routing and user interaction
- Created a MongoDB database to manage back-end data
- Used EJS and CSS to create a responsive front-end on mobile and desktop

## **EDUCATION**

General Assembly Remote

Software Engineering Immersive

July 2023 - Present

• Full-stack software engineering immersive student in an intensive, 24-week, 450+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies. Developed a portfolio of individual and group projects.

# **Bunker Hill Community College**

Boston, MA

Engineering Program

Sept 2021 onward